# **Tyler Mayes**

# Junior Web Developer Indianapolis, IN 317-851-7061 | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

## About Me

I am an Indy based web developer and soldier with experience in front end and back end web development. I have worked with many modern development technologies, with particular expertise in JavaScript, React, RESTful API's, and UI design.

# Education

Eleven Fifty Academy, Full-Stack Development, 09/2019-Present

- Learn to code web pages using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Version control and collaborative software development with Git and GitHub.
- Building secure full-stack applications by leveraging common design and architectural patterns like MVC and REST.
- Safely modeling and storing data in SQL and NoSQL databases.
- Consuming and integrating third-party API's in an application.
- Front-end web application development with modern JavaScript frameworks such as Angular or React.

# **Experience**

US Army, 04/2018-Present

#### Infantryman:

- Trained in combat, life saving techniques, and physical performance.
- Partake in combat patrols on foot and in vehicles.
- Evaluate terrain and record topographical information.
- Work and train in squads of 10-13 in modern combat scenarios.
- Trained and qualified in firing/assembling carbine rifles and assault weapons.
- Learn about leadership and teamwork through vigorous, high-stress training.

#### Infantry Team Leader:

- Directly responsible for the well being, physical readiness, morale, and discipline of 3-4 soldiers within a 13-man squad.
- Lead team of soldiers through modern combat scenarios.
- Responsible of the individual training and maintenance of their equipment.

#### Guitar Center, 05/2018-04/2019

#### Lessons Manager:

- Managed Guitar Center lessons department.
- Coordinated scheduling between students/instructors.
- Created advertisements promoting the lessons program.
- Ensured student and instructor success by tracking student progress and discussing teaching techniques with instructors.
- Hosted/coordinated lessons sponsored events such as open houses, jam nights, and recitals.
- Oversaw a team of instructors and accommodate accordingly to their needs/wants.

#### Drum Sales Associate:

- Recommended merchandise based on customer needs.
- Interfaced with customers, determine needs, provide recommendations, and up-sell services.
- Increased purchase totals by recommending additional items/programs such as memberships and store sponsored credit cards.
- Described merchandise and explain product operation to customers.
- Maintained knowledge of current promotions, exchange guidelines, payment policies, and security practices.

## <u>Skills</u>

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- React, Angular, Node, Express
- NoSQL, Git, Github
- REST, MVC
- Full-stack development, UI/UX design
- Leadership, communication, attention to detail

# Certifications

JavaScript Gold Badge from Eleven Fifty Academy - View Certification